Hallelujah! (Amen)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
BELIEVE AND BE FILLED WITH THE HOLY SPIRIT
How can we believe in order to be filled by the Spirit of God?
That is the question you need to ask yourself.
How can I believe in order to be filled? Because
Without being filled, you can not live right?
It's difficult to live right without being filled.
So difficult to live right.
And You cannot obey the written Word without being filled.
Without being filled, it's like you are without a Helper.
because the Holy Spirit is our Helper
How can one live without a Helper in times of temptation? Can you see?
Hallelujah!
So let's take our reading.
I will take it from the position of faith.
The Book of Hebrews, let's take our reading.
That is chapter 4.
"Therefore, since the promise of entering his rest still stands,
let us be careful that none of you be found to have fallen short of it.
Verse 2: For we also have had the good news proclaimed to us just as they did;
but the message they heard was of no value to them.
because they did not share the faith of those who obeyed.
Verse 3; Now we who have believed enter that rest , just as God has said....
So let me take you to verse 10.
for anyone who enters God's rest also rests from their works,(from your tension, pressure)just as God did from his.
Let us, therefore, make every effort to enter that rest, so that no one will perish.
by following their example of disobedience."
Hallelujah!
So that is Hebrew 4; you take your reading from verse 1 good.
You also find time to read the book of James verse 2 from 14 to the end, that will really help.
The Book of John 16 verse 12 to the end.
And the Book of John 14 from verse 15 to the end.
And the Book of John 7 starting your reading from verse 37-39.
We just have to take from the angle of faith.
BELIEVE AND BE FILLED WITH THE HOLY SPIRIT
Like I have said,
without being filled, you can not live right.
No one can do the work of goodness; God does.
You can do on your own but for selfish, classic and material reasons.
No one can do the work of obedience but God does as He wills.
You can do it, take note of that.
You can be obedient as a man but for reason known to you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In that Book of John 7 verse 37-39
Jesus said, "If you believe in Me, you will receive the Holy Spirit."
The question you need to ask yourself: Did you receive the Holy Spirit when you believed?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You ask that your question - you say you are a believer; we agree you are a believer.
But did you receive the Holy Spirit, when the Father said: 'If you believe in Me,
you will receive the Holy Spirit."
Jesus said, "Those who believe in Me should receive."
It is His will for every believer to receive, to be filled with the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because without it -
without the Holy Spirit - you can not live right; you can not obey Him.
The Scripture, the Bible - you can not obey the Bible.
It's not possible. So since morning we have been glorifying His name.
We have been singing, reverencing Him. The Bible says:
Wherever Jesus is glorified, the Holy Spirit comes.
It means, without being filled, you can not glorify Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Since morning, you have been dancing. I see everyone dancing: "Be glorified!" Fine.
Wherever Jesus is honoured, the Holy Spirit comes.
It means, you cannot honour Him without the Holy Spirit.
You cannot reverence Him. "Jesus, Jesus!" You see people crying "Jesus".
How will you honour Jesus without the Holy Spirit?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is truth in God's Word.
Without being filled with the Holy Ghost, you cannot understand that truth.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is healing, deliverance, blessing and salvation in the Bible, in God's Word - the Bible you are carrying.
But all these can be unveiled to you, when you are filled with the Holy Ghost.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you are filled with Holy Ghost.
A Christian without being filled with the Holy Ghost is a Christian without a Helper.
In times of tribulation, no Helper.
In times of temptation, no Helper.
In times of trial, no Helper.
He will not permit the test to be too great.
To stay with Jesus is to stay with the Holy Ghost.
That is where our safety lies. Tell your neighbour.
That is where our safety lies.
To stay with Jesus is to stay with the Holy Ghost.
In times of temptation, tribulation, crisis - that is where our safety lies.
Can you see, while you are calling the name of Jesus, and it seems nothing to show?
You keep complaining, too much stress, too much tension, stress, tension.
To stay with Jesus is to stay with the Holy Ghost.
That is where our safety lies.
When you call Jesus without being filled, you can not see Jesus on the scene.
So many claim to be Christians.
Many of us claim to be believers - without being filled.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It's a crisis.Tell your neighbour, it's a crisis.
You say I'm your father and I am not your father. I don't even know you.
There is no way I can know you without the Holy Ghost.
But you keep claiming I'm your father.
There is no way I can be your father without the Holy Ghost.
You keep saying I'm your father but there is no way I can be your father without Holy Ghost.
It's a crisis.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many Christians today do not know how to believe and express their faith.
Because the Bible says
there is power in our mouth. The belief in our hearts is released by faith out of our mouths.
But many of us today don't know how to believe and express our faith. Simple.
Faith is expressed through work.
By this work, faith is perfected.
Faith without work is dead.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And what is that work?
Let me give you one good example:
After prayer, you believe it is not going to rain and at the same time
you carry an umbrella along.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me? That is a simple example I can give you.
After you pray, you are about to go to work, and you look at the sky, it seems to be darker,
as if it's about to rain.
As a Christian, you pray. After prayer, you believe
it will not rain.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At the same time, you carry along an umbrella.
What is that for, as a Christian - the umbrella you carry?
This puts your faith to question.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This nullifies your faith.
This is a form of unbelief.
In case it rains, you bring out your umbrella.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Inconsistency of your belief makes you to carry an umbrella.
In case it rains - in case it does not rain.
But after you have prayed and God is not a man.
I don't know whether it will rain or it's not going to rain.
Inconsistency of your belief makes you to carry an umbrella along, in case it rains.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God is not a man; only faith pleases Him.
This means our heart is uneasy and restless.
This means our heart is what?
That is why we carry what? Umbrella.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This shows that we have not yet believed.
When one believes, he is at rest.
When a person believes, he will no longer worry or doubt.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Even your business, you really show that you are not a Christian.
There are so many business cards you have - in case this fails, you do this.
You are a contractor, you are this. Even you express it in the life of your children.
First choice, second choice.
You train them with unbelief.
If you believe in God in a certain matter, you should have a work of faith in that matter.
Are you with me? Tell your neighbour:
If you believe in God in a certain matter, you should have work of faith in that matter.
You believe it will not rain - why do you carry an umbrella?
That shows that something is wrong with your faith; that shows your faith is false.
I will take it one by one because I want to lead you to the Spirit of God.
I just want to carry you there. I will carry you by force.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you insist, I know what to do.
You can resist, I know what to do.
But I don't want to rush you. I want to take you like Sunday school, kindergarten.
"A,B,C,D". Next, tomorrow we start from "E,F,G".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know the work of faith now.
Faith is expressed through work; by this work, faith is perfected.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You pray over some trouble but you are busy planning on your own, worried and full of anxiety,
as if you have never prayed at all.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You pray over some trouble but you are busy planning your own strategy,
in case that prayer is not answered. Strategy where: "I bought a ticket, I will go and see a certain person..."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"Witchdoctor..." Strategy, tactic, busy planning your own strategy.
Worry and anxiety as, if you have never prayed at all.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And prayer of faith must be followed by an absolute trust in God
that He is now working out the answer.
But the opposite is your case. Your issue is a different one, and you want to receive Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour.
Prayer of faith must be followed by an absolute trust in God
that He is now working out the answer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But opposite is the case.
You attain big anointing, you run after the small anointing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You run into upper anointing, you run into small anointing.
Tell me why it will not be affected, your life.
You run to specialist, professor who is specialized on a certain matter. After leaving the place,
you now run to quack people, those who kill people to treat you again.
Tell me why this quack thing will not spoil the one of specialist.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A lot of people have touched you, you are always to pray for, you don't know who is praying for you -
whether he is a religious man, whether he is this, whether he is a spiritualist, a lot of hands.
After prayer and you have been blessed, a lot of hands will remove those blessings again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"Pray for me" - and you don't know who is praying for you -
whether he is removing the anointing in your life or he is decreasing or multiplying,
or he is dividing the anointing in your life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why you see people receiving breakthrough, after a while - again downfall.
Because he is running from one specialist to quack,
to those who can divide his life. This is life we live today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you know who is praying for you, you will not want him to pray for you.
Because he is going to destroy you.
And if you know who is praying for you, you will ask him to pray for you and be filled with the Holy Ghost.
Say it again.
Believe and be filled with the Holy Spirit.
I can't hear you.
Believe and be filled with the Holy Spirit
The reason why we have to go through faith is very important. We can't just jump.
The Bible says in John 7:37-39, it says:
'If you believe in Me, you will receive the Holy Ghost.'
If I start there, it will be very difficult for you to understand what I am talking about.
But the whole thing comes from faith.
So we enter through the angle of faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The tablet, the medicine doctor has given you...
If you don't believe in God with medicine, you cannot believe in God without medicine.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say: "This my tablet, I don't know - whether I should take it. Is it Jesus wanting me to..."
If you don't believe in God with the tablet, the medicine you have,
you cannot believe in Him without the tablet.
The tablet, the medicine is nature. It's mere nature, it was fathomed from the nature,
and nature is of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You see, when I say I can't see any Christian. I am only looking at religious people.
I repeat again. Where is Christian here?
Going by the message, where is Christian?
So I need to explain. This is what I have explained today.
BELIEVE AND BE FILLED WITH THE HOLY SPIRIT
This is a common thing. The issue of umbrella I used is a common thing.
I mean, there is Christian here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Christian without a Helper.
You need a Helper in times of temptation, tribulation
because He promised He will not leave us without a Helper.
So please work on this message. Work on it.
I have given you those tests. Begin to work on it. Work on it, work on it.
And don't forget about your business of the today.
Meditation. Constant meditation. Continue to meditate.
Don't deceive yourself with prayer, shouting.
You need to know what would have come if that prayer...
You have not reached that level of offering, when you stand up and begin to say:
"In Jesus' name, give me biscuit. Give me bread." Do you know the Jesus you are talking to?
If you know Him, He will reply to you.
But you always talk and He never talks.
Your prayer is one sided.You always talk in your prayer but you never hear the One you are talking to:
"Ok, it's alright, don't worry. I will not give you now, so please, the reason why I will not give you
is because of this, because of that, ok, it's alright". Before you say "In Jesus' name. Amen."
But you never hear from Him. It's only you that always talk in the prayer,
and prayer is two-sided.
It's what?
Two-sided conversation - you talk and Jesus talks.
"In Jesus' name, I need biscuit." He will tell you: "Ok, that biscuit, don't worry - I will give you not now."
You can shift your request again: "Ok, if you are not giving me biscuit, when are you going to give me, sir?"
"Ok, I will give you at the right time." - "Ok, sir."
But do you hear from Him?
But it's you that always talk and talk and talk. When someone knock son your door, you open it.
You ignore your prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So now start from the foundation. Don't let us deceive ourselves. Meditation now.
Prepare your heart for God.
Your heart is not a dwelling place yet.
You have to prepare your heart.
There's a conflict between the flesh and spirit; there is a division.
Go - don't go, for - against, in your heart. A lot is going on in your heart.
Get your heart set by meditation,
hymns, spiritual songs, melodies
Get your heart ready; He will soon enter.
When He enters, you will just see prayer coming naturally. It comes -
not the one you fashion, not the one you form by yourself.
You want to pray: "I have a headache, Lord Jesus, can You heal me?"
As if Jesus does not know that you have headache.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When He is not dead. "I have cancer, heal me, Lord."
As if He Himself does not know you have cancer.
Isn't He is your Creator?
How can your Creator not know you? And you are now telling your Creator what you are going through,
ignorant.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"I am barren, I have been looking for fruit of the womb, Lord, deliver me".
How can you believe that God does not know what you are going through.
You are a clay. You are just a pen - that you use pen to write. But the One that is holding the pen -
that is your creator. And you - pen that we are using to write.
How can that pen now be telling the One that is holding it: "Look, I don't have ink inside me?
I can not write anymore." If you hear from the pen like that you will not drop it and run away?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are Christians without a Helper.
Tell your neighbour.
You are a Christian without a Helper because you are not yet filled.
Tell your neighbour
If you are not yet filled, you can be a Christian as you proclaim, without a Helper.
Helper in times of temptation, in times of tribulation. Helper -
He helps us in our struggles.
He is there in our struggles.
You are here, you know what I have gone through in this ministry.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know what I have gone through. Without that Helper - do you think I can still...
It's not possible. Even all of you, you know in the past, when you were at home,
you were not be able to eat. When you were eating, you dropped your food and said:
"Is that the end of the Synagogue?
T.B. Joshua - that is the end. What is going to happen next?" Oh my God.
That Helper, you need.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT Monica Asefa 07/01/19
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 17/01/2019